JAMES SINNOTT

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A Junior Fullstack Software Developer with a background in Computer Games Development and Civil Engineering. Almost three years commercial experience working as a Software Engineer with EasyGo in the Electric Vehicle Industry. Comfortable in Frontend and Backend Development, skilled in a number of programming languages and frameworks.

WORK HISTORY

Software Engineer, 01/2022 - 06/2024

EasyGo, Maynooth, Co. Kildare

I worked on various projects (primarily in Java Spring Boot) to improve the efficiency of EasyGo's business. Some of these projects as well as my daily responsibilities at EasyGo were:

- Automatic usage report generation sent by SendGrid email to EasyGo clients.
- Creation of a multi-threaded realtime dashboard application.
- EasyGo's daily transactions retrieved (via Urchin API) and stored in Mongo for the Accounts team.
- Fob mailer generated by Webscraper.
- Creation of a Heatmap in AngularJS to show EasyGo charging activity by different categories.
- Maintenance of a Frontend Dev Site which aids in some tasks i.e Drag-and-drop CSV from Ocean (Backend system) to generate usage report in PDF format.
- Testing & uploading of EasyGo apps on Google Play Console and Apple Store.
- Support for electricians with charger maintenance via Ocean monitoring.
- Customer/Client support via emails/calls.
- Training in new members of staff.

Civil Engineer's Assistant, 06/2017 - 09/2020 Martin Sinnott B.E. Chartered Civil Engineer, Enniscorthy, Co. Wexford

- Responsible for: drawing plans of houses using AutoCAD, onsite taping, handling phone calls, doing up planning applications to be sent to the local authority
- I directly reported to my employer on the progress of my work and had the experience of working closely with clients to achieve their goals.

Software Development Intern, 03/2015 - 09/2015 IT Carlow GameCORE Research Centre, Carlow, Co. Carlow

 Collaborated in a three man team on a gamification project to create an app to help people track their fitness using the Fitbit

- P Enniscorthy, Co.Wexford
- 0873689476
- JamesRichardSinnott@gmail.c
- lrish
- https://github.com/JamesSinnott1994
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/j amessinnott1/

SKILLS

- HTML / CSS / JavaScript
- JQuery / Bootstrap
- Python / Flask / Django
- SQL / MongoDB
- Java / Spring Boot / Hibernate
- PHP
- C#, C++
- Git / Jira / Docker
- NodeJS / AngularJS / ReactJS / ExpressJS
- AWS
- Testing and maintenance
- AutoCAD

- I was in charge of: data retrieval (via the Fitbit API), database management, linux and apache server setup and maintenance, push notifications, and selenium testing
- My teammates and I went through the SCRUM agile software development process for this project
- I spoke directly to my employer about the progress of my team
- I developed software for the Android and iOS platforms using JavaScript, HTML5, and Python and used MySQL to manage the database.

EDUCATION

Diploma of Higher Education, Fullstack Software Development, 10/2020 - 12/2021

Code Institute - Ireland

Remote course that focused on developing four major projects in the categories of:

- 1. User-Centric Front End Development (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap) A static website created for fans of "The Saw Doctors".
- 2. Interactive Front End Development (JavaScript, jQuery) An interactive Quiz Game made with the help of the Open Trivia API.
- 3. Data-Centric Development (Python, Flask, SQL) A book review and recommendation site.
- 4. Full Stack Frameworks (Django) An online gaming store site.

05/2017 - 05/2020 Treehouse - Online Coding Courses

Bachelor of Science (Honours), Computer Games Development, 09/2012 - 05/2016 IT Carlow

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

In my spare time I enjoy reading, travelling, music, swimming, kayaking, puzzle solving and always learning new things.